[
    {
        "tlk_id": 15,
        "tile1": 91,
        "x_pos1": 29,
        "y_pos1": 9,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 0,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Barren",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A small child.",
            "job": "No job.",
            "heal": "O.K.",
            "keyword1": "MANT",
            "keyword2": "A   ",
            "answer1": "I know it well, it is 'OM'.",
            "answer2": "A",
            "yesnoquestion": "A",
            "yesanswer": "A",
            "noanswer": "A"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 14,
        "tile1": 88,
        "x_pos1": 11,
        "y_pos1": 3,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Ambule",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A grimy beggar.",
            "job": "I beg for but for a single gold piece!",
            "heal": "So-so.",
            "keyword1": "BEG ",
            "keyword2": "MANT",
            "answer1": "Oh, please... Oh, please...",
            "answer2": "Ask the child named Barren.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Wilt thou please give me a gold piece?",
            "yesanswer": "Dear kind soul.",
            "noanswer": "Stingy, I know thou hast many!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 13,
        "tile1": 61,
        "x_pos1": 12,
        "y_pos1": 15,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "the Ankh of Spirituality",
            "pronoun": "It",
            "look": "A silver ankh.",
            "job": "I keep the secret of the rune.",
            "heal": "Strong.",
            "keyword1": "RUNE",
            "keyword2": "OM  ",
            "answer1": "Mantra?",
            "answer2": "Search for the rune of spirituality in the treasure chamber of Britannia!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Hast thou found the shrine?",
            "yesanswer": "Good!",
            "noanswer": "Enter the gate of full moons!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 12,
        "tile1": 36,
        "x_pos1": 12,
        "y_pos1": 16,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 1,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "White",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A gallant fighter.",
            "job": "I quest.",
            "heal": "Excellent!",
            "keyword1": "QUES",
            "keyword2": "DANG",
            "answer1": "Many quests are very dangerous!",
            "answer2": "I am not afraid of tomorrow; I have seen yesterday and I love today.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou fearless in all thing?",
            "yesanswer": "Boastful fool!",
            "noanswer": "Danger is real!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 11,
        "tile1": 34,
        "x_pos1": 13,
        "y_pos1": 15,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Dickens",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A wise bard.",
            "job": "I write stories.",
            "heal": "O.K.",
            "keyword1": "STOR",
            "keyword2": "SPIR",
            "answer1": "Stories are good for the spirit!",
            "answer2": "Remember, no one is useless in this world who lightens the burdens of others!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou good in nature?",
            "yesanswer": "Be sure thy net good well exceeds thy net evil!",
            "noanswer": "I see."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 10,
        "tile1": 32,
        "x_pos1": 12,
        "y_pos1": 14,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 3,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Carlyle",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A wise mage.",
            "job": "I write magic.",
            "heal": "Fine.",
            "keyword1": "MAGI",
            "keyword2": "BELI",
            "answer1": "One lives by believing in something.",
            "answer2": "Great discoveries are made by those whose feelings run ahead of their thinking.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou believe in magic?",
            "yesanswer": "Magic missiles need but 1 part ash!",
            "noanswer": "I see."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 9,
        "tile1": 37,
        "x_pos1": 9,
        "y_pos1": 26,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Romasco",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A short dumpy man with a book.",
            "job": "I am a teacher, I enrich young minds.",
            "heal": "I am fine.",
            "keyword1": "TEAC",
            "keyword2": "WORD",
            "answer1": "I teach of the abyss.",
            "answer2": "Seek Zair the Wise in Paws for more on the word.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Know ye of the abyss?",
            "yesanswer": "A word of passage is needed at the last gate!",
            "noanswer": "Learn!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 8,
        "tile1": 45,
        "x_pos1": 26,
        "y_pos1": 15,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 3,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Michaelangelo",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A skilled ranger",
            "job": "I strive along the path.",
            "heal": "Well.",
            "keyword1": "PATH",
            "keyword2": "JOUR",
            "answer1": "Success is a journey, not a destination.",
            "answer2": "May thou always desire more than thou can accomplish!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou far along the path?",
            "yesanswer": "This is good.",
            "noanswer": "Fear not thou shalt be."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 92,
        "x_pos1": 6,
        "y_pos1": 10,
        "move": 1,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 92,
        "x_pos1": 5,
        "y_pos1": 21,
        "move": 1,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 7,
        "tile1": 83,
        "x_pos1": 12,
        "y_pos1": 29,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 0,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Buddha",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A great philosopher.",
            "job": "I teach.",
            "heal": "I am well.",
            "keyword1": "TEAC",
            "keyword2": "NOBL",
            "answer1": "When one has pity on all living creatures then is one noble.",
            "answer2": "If one speaks or acts with pure thought, happiness will follow like a shadow that never leaves.",
            "yesnoquestion": "A",
            "yesanswer": "A",
            "noanswer": "A"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 6,
        "tile1": 45,
        "x_pos1": 29,
        "y_pos1": 2,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Mitre",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A radiant ranger.",
            "job": "I am reading the wizard's journal.",
            "heal": "I am fine.",
            "keyword1": "JOUR",
            "keyword2": "STON",
            "answer1": "It tells of the white stone.",
            "answer2": "It is no longer in the dungeon Hythloth, it is gone!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Wilt thou try to recover it?",
            "yesanswer": "Ask of the stone at the Tap in Trinsic!",
            "noanswer": "Too bad."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 5,
        "tile1": 89,
        "x_pos1": 2,
        "y_pos1": 0,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Granted",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A hungry beggar.",
            "job": "I beg for food and money.",
            "heal": "I am not at all well.",
            "keyword1": "FOOD",
            "keyword2": "MONE",
            "answer1": "To eat!",
            "answer2": "To buy food!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Wilt thou give me food or money?",
            "yesanswer": "In return I will tell thee that the ankh knows of the rune and my friend Ambule knows the mantra!",
            "noanswer": "Jerk!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 4,
        "tile1": 33,
        "x_pos1": 8,
        "y_pos1": 5,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Presto",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A very small wizard.",
            "job": "I cast great big spells!",
            "heal": "Superior!",
            "keyword1": "SPEL",
            "keyword2": "NIGH",
            "answer1": "I can cast: jinx, kill, and view!",
            "answer2": "Yes, ask the barkeep at 'The Axe-n-Ale' in Vesper about nightshade.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou know what these spells have in common?",
            "yesanswer": "What?",
            "noanswer": "Guess!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 3,
        "tile1": 45,
        "x_pos1": 22,
        "y_pos1": 16,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Santayana",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A tall ranger.",
            "job": "I carry the light within my heart.",
            "heal": "I am alive.",
            "keyword1": "LIGH",
            "keyword2": "PHIL",
            "answer1": "The light of philosophy.",
            "answer2": "In philosophical minds the familiar excites wonder!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou always tread the right path?",
            "yesanswer": "Doubtful!",
            "noanswer": "Few can, but strive to do so!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 2,
        "tile1": 56,
        "x_pos1": 10,
        "y_pos1": 24,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Emerson",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "An injured man.",
            "job": "I seek the spiritual path.",
            "heal": "I am grievously wounded.",
            "keyword1": "SPIR",
            "keyword2": "WOUN",
            "answer1": "Spiritual is stronger than any material force.",
            "answer2": "Nothing can bring thee peace but the triumph of principles!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou good in spirit?",
            "yesanswer": "A good path.",
            "noanswer": "An evil path!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 82,
        "x_pos1": 24,
        "y_pos1": 18,
        "move": 128,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 83,
        "x_pos1": 21,
        "y_pos1": 12,
        "move": 128,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 83,
        "x_pos1": 5,
        "y_pos1": 3,
        "move": 1,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 82,
        "x_pos1": 6,
        "y_pos1": 28,
        "move": 128,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 1,
        "tile1": 45,
        "x_pos1": 10,
        "y_pos1": 15,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 0,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Shamino",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A solemn ranger.",
            "job": "I seek the inner light.",
            "heal": "I am well.",
            "keyword1": "LIGH",
            "keyword2": "TRUT",
            "answer1": "I seek the \"one great truth\"!",
            "answer2": "That which lies within the codex!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou seek this \"truth\"?",
            "yesanswer": "Some things take forever but brick by brick mountains can be built!",
            "noanswer": "Alas."
        }
    }
]